Kimberley Dobney

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER





Profile

I am a methodical and creative full-stack web developer with a design background. I have just completed a four-month full-stack software development at <u>iO Academy</u>. In my free time, I enjoy making clothes, running and watching live music. In my time as a designer, I created UI's for websites and apps as well as developed interesting brands with accompanying guidelines. After having a glimpse into the dev world and feeling restricted by the limitations of Squarespace I decided it was time I learned how to code.

Projects

Working in a team of eight students I have learnt how to manage agile projects with Github and SCRUM (I am now a certified SCRUM master) as well as how to complete code reviews. More projects can be found in my <u>portfolio</u>.

Snake Sweeper

JavaScript Game (JavaScript, HTML, CSS)





We manipulated the DOM using event listeners and conditionals to create the interactive elements of the game. I focused on generating the randomised grid when a new game is started and creating functionality that triggers a dynamic modal to appear if the game is won/lost.

Muppet World

OOP listing app (PHP, OOP, SQL, HTML and CSS)





We created this app in OOP applying SOLID principles where possible. I worked on designing, creating and implementing the wireframes. As well as the hydrator/entity classes to receive and display data from a SQL database. The project utilised autoloading and namespacing throughout, validated and sanitised all user inputs before database insertion and unit tested our methods with PHPUnit.

Social Media Site

Full-stack, team project (Node.js, Sequal Pro, React, JS, Material UI, HTML)



Front



Back

We worked in a scrum team of four to create the front and back end of the app. I designed and implemented the wireframes using material UI and created the routes to the database in Node. Each user profile dynamically displays the users own posts, bio and user name. We applied front end validation to the sign-up and login pages, as well as JSON web tokens to restrict access to protected pages.



Previous Employment

Citizen Tickets

Freelance Marketing Lead July 2021 - Oct 2021

- Social media marketing and planning
- Writing blog posts and interviewing clients

Wase

Brand and Community Manager August 2020 - July 2021

- Redesigned internal and external brand presence using Adobe Creative Cloud
- · Managed social media accounts
- Collaborated with external Developers to design website and app

Turn and Flow

Co-founder

August 2019 - July 2021

- Designed a product-service-system to incorporate menstrual waste into mainstream composting systems
- Developed a brand, social presence, video content and a Squarespace website using Adobe Creative Cloud
- Crowdfunded to run a £23k study at Cranfield University

Film Website

Freelance Web Design

2020

 Worked closely with Niamh to develop a personal brand that reflected her work and used square space to build it.

Education

Full Stack Software

Development

iO Academy

A four-month intensive Bootcamp in full-stack software development.

Product Design Engineering

Brunel University London (2:1)

A three-year degree with one year model making placement.

A-levels Queen Elizabeth Grammar School

MathsMechanics A*, Physics A, English Language B

Professional Achievements

Certified Scrum Master 2021 - Scrum Alliance Oatly Je Ne Sais Quis Award - Turn and Flow 2020

D&AD side-hustle awards finalist - For Turn and Flow's creative direction and branding

Contact

07530640323

kim.dobney@yahoo.co.uk



